[XYLO] Teoritta, we did it.
[TEORITTA] Yes, as all
surely knew we would.
I permit you to praise me
in honor
of our inevitable victory.
"You're a truly great goddess.
Excellent work today, Teoritta."
[scoffs]
Excellent work, Teoritta.
You really are a great goddess.
[Teoritta chuckles softly]
[XYLO] And you're not alone,
you know.
Wanting to be praised
for doing your job well.
I think we're all like that.
Some people
may want it so badly,
they're willing
to risk their lives for it.
Yes.
[♪ inspirational music playing]
[sighs]
-[groans]
-[Xylo grunts]
[IRI] Help!
Please help me. It's my dad!
A monster got him.
He's hurt. [sobs]
[Xylo grunts] Someone else
to protect.
You stay here.
-I can take care--
-Do not despair, small one.
Hey!
[TEORITTA] All will be well.
For you are now
under the protection
of the goddess Teoritta
and her valiant knight,
Xylo Forbartz.
Let's make haste
to find your father the aid
that he needs.
First, may I ask your name?
[sobbing] My--
my name is Ir-- [groans]
[muffled] Oh, no!
Are you injured as well?
Teoritta!
[sword slashes]
[IRI] Die.
[sword clinks]
[grunts]
[groans]
[Xylo grunts]
[TSAV] Oh, whoopsies!
I just shot a kid, I think.
I mean, they're weird.
[VENETIM] Tsav! Please tell me
you did not just
kill a civilian!
[TSAV] It looked like she
was attacking Teoritta.
-Like I said, they're weird!
-[VENETIM] Weird? Try "insane"!
[Iri retches] I will not allow.
[Xylo grunts]
[Iri yells]
[gasps, grunts]
Teoritta!
-[panting]
-[XYLO] Are you hurt?
I told you that you
should stay back.
-Xylo.
-Yes?
It appears...
learning to use this
may prove a worthwhile endeavor.
Huh.
[sighs]
So that's how you
blocked its attack.
I'll have to buy you
an even better one, then.
And train you up.
We need to be careful.
A faerie disguising itself
as a human.
It might have been Spriggan
that ambushed us.
I guess the Demon Blight
sees you as a threat.
One it would like to eliminate.
Good. I could want
for nothing more.
[scoffs]
You goddesses.
Never can make anything easy,
can you?
Right. Back to the barracks,
and those good-for-nothing
bastards.
Our allies. Let us now return
to their sides where we belong!
-But before we go...
-Huh?
...you know what to do, yes?
-Ah...
-[crackling]
Hmm.
Come, my knight!
Say the words!
-[Xylo gasps]
-With utmost thoroughness
and gusto,
praise your brilliant goddess!
[indistinct chatter]
About 130 evacuees
have made it to the stronghold
and no fatalities.
I would say
that the Thirteenth Order
has done itself proud.
Captain Kivia has really whipped
us all into shape.
[SIENA] But I haven't seen her
or the infantry lieutenant
anywhere.
[Zofflec sighs]
Maybe they're letting us bask
in the spotlight for once.
They usually lead the charge.
We deserve a chance
to shine now and then.
[Siena sighs]
[MARLEN] You fought well today.
All of you.
Let the military and the Temple
continue to work together...
[FRENCI] Sorry
to keep you waiting.
What did you learn? Tell me.
-[SOLDIER] Right!
-[MARLEN] Now, all units
return to your posts...
I'm afraid it appears
your suspicions were correct.
[both gasp]
[indistinct chatter]
[water splashing]
[Spriggan groans]
With these injuries,
I must focus on healing myself.
[grunts]
After that, a new host.
[grunts in pain]
[RHYNO] Oh, look what the cat
dragged in.
I was hoping we'd cross paths.
Guess my wish came true.
Huh, Spriggan?
[gasps]
Oh, dear. Don't tell me
you didn't know.
Whenever a Demon Blight
is corrupting an area,
they give off a unique, uh,
what would you call it?
A unique wave, of sorts.
It's something
that other demon lords
can sense.
In fact,
that's how I was able
-to track you down.
-Wait.
[RHYNO] I'm not finished.
Hear me out, won't you?
I happen to be a member
of the penal hero unit.
But you see, the crime
I am so very guilty of
is the simplest
and least offensive
of my comrades.
Guilt's a strange concept,
but I know I'm right.
[Spriggan gasps]
[RHYNO] Can you guess my crime?
[gasps in fear]
Give up yet?
I love to kill my own kind.
I take great pleasure in it.
It's just how I am.
[laughs]
Aren't humans great?
That trait is so common
among their kind,
they actually consider it
a rather boring motive.
-[laughs]
-Go away!
-I mean it! Get back!
-[RHYNO] Being boring
-is an amazing gift.
-Right now!
-[RHYNO] That's why...
-If you don't,
-you'll be sorry!
-[RHYNO]...I've completely
submitted to them.
I'll do pretty much anything
they ask of me.
-[screams]
-I'm currently learning
about ethics, you know,
which is why
I see things clearly.
I realize,
from the Demons Blight's
perspective,
I'm a homicidal maniac.
-[Spriggan screams]
-Slaughtering my own kind
for the thrill of it
makes me the most hackneyed,
cliched version of a murderer
you could imagine.
-[Spriggan screams]
-But in the eyes of humans,
I'm a brave champion for good.
Isn't it just baffling?
[chuckles]
To be honest,
I'm still trying to work out
the logic behind it myself.
-Get away from me!
-Exhilarating!
Your screams
are music to my ears.
I am enamored with that sound.
Thrilling. Makes me
want to savor
-killing you.
-[thud]
[groans]
[RHYNO] Ah, how rude of me.
I've yet to introduce myself.
I am a Demon Lord, of course.
Puck Puca.
Though naturally,
the humans call me
by the name
of this body's original owner.
So I go by Rhyno these days.
Well, it's been fun.
-Pleasant dreams, Spriggan.
-[Spriggan groans]
[splattering]
[thud]
[BOOJUM] Quite impossible
to carry out my orders now.
It's starting to look like
I will have to disappoint
our king once more.
[bee buzzing]
[BOOJUM] Yes.
I had a blood puppet
take my place in battle.
The Holy Sword
is far too dangerous.
It's apparent
I'll need a great deal
of human blood
to kill those two.
[distant rumbling]
[MARLEN] I heard
about your incredible deeds.
Truly valorous. I'm impressed.
[KIVIA] Thank you
for the praise.
You deserve commendation
as well.
I heard the rumors.
They say your leadership
was extraordinary.
It was merely good fortune.
Perhaps I was granted a blessing
from the saints of old.
There's no need to be humble.
Your deeds will likely earn you
a position of leadership
among the High Priests.
If they see fit to bestow
upon me such an honor,
I'll begin
with a staff overhaul.
As of now,
we are sorely lacking in unity.
Furthermore, Patausche,
I will promote you
to a position more befitting
of your accomplishments.
A staff overhaul? I see.
In truth,
we both know what that means.
You intend
to fill Temple leadership
with coexisters.
[distant thunderclap]
[MARLEN] Did you interrogate
Lideo Sodrick?
I know the truth
about the coexister envoy
he spoke of.
It was Mahaeyzel Zelkoff.
All priests and Temple officials
invoke that name often.
They ask him for luck in battle.
How is that relevant?
Because in the inner lands
and elsewhere,
they pronounce the name
as "Zelkoof."
He called him ”Zelkoff,"
just like us northerners.
Someone with the funds
to hire the Adventurers Guild.
Someone born in the north
and involved with the Temple.
It certainly
narrows down the suspects.
Uncle,
when I was young,
I was desperate
to experience the world.
You alone
opened the door for me.
[MARLEN] Hmm.
When I chose to cut my own path,
to live a life wholly distinct
from that of my parents,
you gave me everything
I needed to succeed,
including this sword.
[inaudible]
Remember sneaking me out
into the city?
You used the same alias
every time.
Always "Zelkoff."
You still remember that?
Those memories are precious.
That said,
I also made sure
to check your activity records.
Take this recent battle,
for example.
The unit that first reported
the presence of faeries
in the Inland District.
I asked which one it was,
and you told me seven, one,
one, zero.
Imagine my surprise
that no such unit exists.
[MARLEN] You never cease
to amaze me.
Hmm.
[grunts]
Why, Uncle?
Why would you agree
to work with the coexisters?
For the sake of the people
I hold dear to me.
-[Rajit gasps]
-I order you to remain
where you are!
[MARLEN] I did it for myself
-and for my family.
-Uncle!
[MARLEN] And of course,
for the devout followers
of the Temple.
I want to save them all.
[Kivia grunts]
[MARLEN] Patausche.
Humanity will lose this battle.
If nothing else,
I want to protect the righteous
of heart and my beloved family.
There is no other way.
[KIVIA] Hmm.
How kind.
Unless you're not family
-or a follower--
-[MARLEN] The rest are none
of my concern.
[gasps]
[MARLEN] That's just
human nature. Is it not?
Or do you wish to be the sort
of high-minded paragon
who saves complete strangers,
even at the cost
of her own family?
You're wrong, Uncle!
I want to be--
[MARLEN] You're still
that naive, little girl
who never lost
her idealistic immaturity.
Patausche, it is time
to grow up.
Fight for what matters,
such as your family
and those close to you.
Help me shape the world
as a coexister.
Together, you and I
will act as the shepherds
of our dear flock.
Please! Don't you see that--
[MARLEN] Nothing
can save humanity
from the Demon Blight.
We'll be among the select few
with authority
that will allow us
to guide the survivors.
They'll be relying on us,
and so we must lead them
down the--
Not another word!
[♪ pensive music playing]
[Kivia sobs]
[KIVIA] I'm sorry. Truly.
I always looked up to you
as my hero.
I mean that
from the bottom of my heart!
[continues sobbing]
Why are you crying?
[Kivia sobs]
[KIVIA] I'm not like you.
Even those who have nothing
to do with me.
Strangers with names
and faces, I'll never know.
I can't abandon them.
It's wrong!
That mindset is unusual
and self-righteous.
It's most disheartening.
Perhaps a savior complex
stemming
from an overinflated ego.
Suppose I only have
myself to blame
-for raising you that way.
-[KIVIA] That's enough!
-Rajit, arrest him!
-Right!
[sobbing] Uncle.
You must atone--
[Rajit gasps]
-[buzzing]
-[gasps]
-[RAJIT] Captain, move!
-[splattering]
[Kivia exclaims]
[rain pouring]
[MARLEN] Hmm.
[Kivia screams]
[MARLEN] I hope
you can forgive me,
Patausche.
I truly thought
of you as a daughter.
How disappointing.
[inaudible]
[sword clinks]
[MALE PRIEST 1] Please hurry.
Something's wrong!
-High Priest!
-[all gasp]
[both gasp]
[XYLO] I take it Rhyno
isn't back yet?
Kivia will be pissed
if she finds out.
Unbelievable!
You've got to put that moron
on a chain already, Venetim.
Really? That's pretty rich
coming from you, Jayce.
You should lighten up.
What's so wrong
with letting him
do his own thing out there?
[sighs]
Maybe he's off
looting the wreckage.
Or found some faerie
to mess with for a laugh.
I've seen that guy
bring whole faeries back alive,
never to be seen again.
Right?
-Dotta?
-[DOTTA] Right.
He said he's studying them
or something, I think.
[Xylo grunts]
[Dotta exclaims] Xylo!
Perfect!
Don't forget to save some
for me, bro!
-[Xylo sighs]
-[NORGALLE] Colossal fool!
You dare demand a reward
after such inaction? Not today!
You and Rhyno have much
-to answer for.
-What?
Are you kidding?
I saved the goddess!
That's gotta be worth a sip
-or two.
-Who gives a damn?
-Just let it go already.
-[Neely snorts]
-[steps approaching]
-Huh?
-[FRENCI] Xylo.
-[horse neighs]
[XYLO] Frenci?
You are always such a mess.
Care to explain
why you're sitting
on your laurels?
We're off duty.
You'll have to come back
tomorrow.
[TSAV] If you
are not gonna drink, gimme.
[Xylo grunts]
I'm not in the mood
to take your abuse anyway.
How pathetic.
And you expect
to become a Mastibolt?
You're like a hot springs monkey
in hibernation.
Can I get a moment to relax?
The battle has been settled.
Perhaps.
Unless the attack
on this city was a diversion.
Uh. [gasps]
Hold on.
Are you saying--
[FRENCI] Demon Blight Abaddon.
Its forces breached
the Ninth Order's defenses
and attacked the Second Capital.
-[gasps]
-[Norgalle shivers]
[NORGALLE] My capital city
attacked by the faeries?
And I wasn't there
to lead. To fight.
[FRENCI] They got wind
of our plans in advance
and deftly outmaneuvered us.
You mean...
[FRENCI] Yes.
The Second Capital
has fallen.
[ADHIFF] Second Capital Zeyllent
is the symbol
of the Federated Kingdom
and a crucial spot
for the nation's defense.
Huh.
It's essentially
like taking a blade
and putting it to the throat
of the First Capital
and Galtuile Fortress.
-[people screaming]
-She killed someone
in her own family.
And high up
in the Temple, as well.
[SIENA] Excuse me!
We need to get through!
[Siena, Zofflec gasp]
[MAN 1] How could you kill
High Priest Marlen?
[MAN 2] You deserve
a painful death.
-Filthy heretic!
-Make her suffer!
[MALE SOLDIER] Go on.
Keep moving.
Captain Kivia.
How did this happen?
[people booing, exclaiming]
[MALE INSPECTOR]
Patausche Kivia,
Captain of the Thirteenth Order
of the Holy Knights.
Why did you kill
High Priest Marlen Kivia
and Infantry Lieutenant
Rajit Heathrow?
You can keep asking,
but it's the same answer.
-He was a coexistent and I--
-Liar!
You clearly feared and coveted
High Priest Marlen's
popularity and skill.
So you betrayed humanity,
killing him and your lieutenant.
-[grunts]
-[chains clinking]
[MALE INSPECTOR] All you need
to do is confess
to the undeniable facts.
And I will release you
without delay.
What's going to happen
to my knights?
And the hero unit.
Where are Xylo Forbartz
and the others?
Why aren't you
holding a proper trial?
Let me speak in a court of law!
It seems you need more time
to think it through.
You'll come around eventually.
[grunts]
[rain pouring]
[mouse squeaks]
[footsteps approaching]
[KAFZEN] Forgive
my late arrival.
The discussion took a fair bit
of time to conclude.
[chains clinking]
We weren't positive
that we could add one more.
It was a difficult decision.
[ENFIÉ] Hmm.
[sighs]
You're Patausche Kivia.
Formerly,
captain of the Thirteenth Order
of the Holy Knights.
Your abilities
on the battlefield
are exceptional,
but it was your mental fortitude
that caught us by surprise.
You killed a relative
-to whom you owe a great deal.
-[Kivia gasps]
[KAFZEN] You mercilessly
took the life
of someone you deeply respected,
for the sake
of complete strangers,
making it an action
that transcended any notion
of self-interest.
You have
the unbridled conviction
of a savior,
or perhaps more accurately,
the delusion of one.
How do you know all that?
[KAFZEN] My goddess
has the ability to summon books.
In other words, you might say
she can summon information.
-[ENFIÉ] Hmm.
-[KAFZEN] Hmm?
Ah? No, Enfié.
I haven’t forgotten.
-Thank you.
-[chuckles]
-[chains clinking]
-What is this?
-Are you a Holy Knight?
-[KAFZEN] Hmm?
I am. A knight
of the Twelfth Order.
Which means we
were once associates,
though I know
it seems farfetched.
I have come here
to offer you the chance
to choose your own fate.
You have only two options.
The first, you can be executed
as a member of the coexisters.
The second,
you can become a penal hero
and continue fighting
against the Demon Blight.
[Kivia gasps]
[chuckles]
Heroes are denied
the sweet release of death
and have no freedom whatsoever.
It's a life without glory,
devoted to helping others.
Those nameless strangers.
I wouldn't agree
to such a thing myself.
And to be frank, I don't believe
you're cut out for it, either.
What are they?
What is the hero penalty really?
[sighs]
I'd be more than happy
to tell you everything I can.
I take it
you've heard the rumors
floating around town.
The ones
about our first goddess
and her ability
to summon heroic champions.
Long ago, at the beginning
of the first war,
she called forth warriors
from other worlds.
But the cultural differences
made it hard to communicate.
And so, those in charge
changed their tactics
accordingly.
They summoned the dead
of this world
and deployed them
as their champions instead.
They summoned the dead
of this world.
Then,
the resurrections.
You're remarkably clever.
Heroes stand
on the front lines
in the battle
against the Demon Blight,
and are denied
even the dignity of death
in this endless war.
[KIVIA] So
that's what heroes are.
I can't believe it.
I'm afraid it's true.
And I'll bet you're wondering
how it became
a criminal sentence.
Just take my word for it.
We have our reasons
for that one as well.
By the way,
the first goddess' power
is incredible, but flawed.
I believe you're already aware
of what happens to a person
after too many resurrections.
[gasps]
They lose their memories
little by little.
And their sense of self
is worn away.
Yes, and humans apparently
do possess something similar
to the concept of a soul.
The results
are meaningfully affected
by how clearly
she remembers the target.
It impacts precision
both in regard
to summoning and resurrection.
Though, we do have Enfié.
Her records are a boon.
The first goddess
expends all of her energy
on a single task.
Every day,
she must remember the heroes
and their memories.
Yet her mind has a limit.
I'd say she has room
for just one more hero.
[KIVIA] Humanity's trump card.
But are you certain
it's worth such a heavy cost?
Interesting question.
It is my sincerest hope
that the answer turns out
to be a resounding yes.
Those are all the secrets
I can disclose.
I'll leave
the sacred-seal collar
and "repairs" for another day.
It's time.
Make your choice,
Patausche Kivia.
[KIVIA] Huh.
If I agree to be a hero,
does that mean
you'll get me out of this cell?
[KAFZEN] Of course.
But you'll have to die
before we can begin.
Then I'll carry you out
of here in pieces.
There's no room for compromise.
Put your faith
in the goddess and die.
Or refuse to and die.
Those are the only options
you have.
[♪ pensive music playing]
[KIVIA] Fate is cruel.
Born to a family of priests.
I needed to escape.
My uncle was the only one
who understood me.
And now I've killed him.
Left alone in this dark,
I keep wondering.
What do my knights think of me?
And the hero unit,
what do they make of my crime?
I hope they'll chalk it up
to a fit of madness
because if they hate me
for what I have done...
[sobs]
...if they believe what's said
about me being a coexister
and betraying humanity.
[continues sobbing]
If my knights...
If he were to think that
of me...
[continues sobbing]
...I couldn't bear it!
Well, so be it.
I suppose that if this
will allow me to keep fighting,
then I have no choice.
For all those faceless strangers
I'll never meet,
I swear to fight.
I'll be a hero.
[♪ tense music playing]
[KAFZEN] I had a feeling.
There's no going back on this.
And I don't recommend it.
But I will make certain
this remains a secret.
On a personal level,
I am still vehemently opposed
to making you a hero.
That said,
I feel it's my responsibility
to respect your oath.
Go on.
There's no time to waste.
[chain clinking]
In sacrifice to the lives
of the many,
you have come to this moment,
and I bear witness.
[panting]
[KAFZEN] Patausche Kivia,
it is time I sentence you
to be...
a hero.
[clinking]
[♪ closing theme song playing]
SENTENCED TO BE A HERO